Markets, speculation, and risk. This is
the Chat with Traders podcast.
Hey everyone, welcome back to Chat with
Traders. This is Tessa, your co-host,
and we're in episode 315,
which happens to be the first episode of
2026.
Happy New Year. I wish all of you a
great year ahead. New charts, new data,
better discipline, and a lot of
opportunities. And I think today's
conversation is a great way to kick
things off. Today, my co-host Ian chats
with Jamal Gari, based just outside
Philadelphia.
Jamal first got exposed to markets at
just 14 years old, watching his dad
trade early crypto and a few years later
was placing his own trades while working
at Chipotle as a teenager. Now in his
mid20s, Jamal's path through crypto,
stocks, and then options reflects his
full learning curve, early confidence,
oversized bets, and a painful reset. At
one point, Jamal ran a small account up
aggressively during the postcoid crash
and meme stock era and then gave nearly
all of it back in a single sequence of
trades. What makes his approach
interesting is how he moved away from
simply predicting direction toward
ranking setups, sizing risk accordingly,
and trading volatility and structure
rather than just price. In this
conversation, we talk about the
evolution of his process, the risk
mistakes that nearly ended it, and how
he now approaches options through the
lens of volatility and structure,
including the strategies he's using
inside his own private multistrategy
hedge fund launched last year. Ladies
and gentlemen, we're so pleased to
present Jamal Gari from Pennsylvania.
>> Uh Jamal, how are you doing today?
>> Doing fantastic. How about yourself?
>> Great. Fantastic. It's a pleasure uh
welcoming you to Chat with Traders.
>> Yeah, absolutely pleasure to be here.
I've seen the episodes in the past, so
ready to have a good time.
>> Yeah. Where where are you now?
>> So, I'm I'm in Pennsylvania about 20 30
minutes outside of Philly, actually.
>> Okay. Where whereabouts did you grow up?
So, I grew up in the city of
Philadelphia and then moved out in my
teenage years and then uh bit been in
the area of Bucks County, a little bit
of a small town. Been there ever since.
>> Fantastic. So, tell us about your early
years and and when was the first time
you got attracted to financial markets.
>> Yeah, sure. So, uh it really started
when I was young. um probably about 14
years old when my father got in very
early to crypto when Bitcoin was first
running up and um I was in middle school
uh or a freshman in high school, very
young. I was 14 years old and he was
just showing me what what he did and I I
would sat I would sit there watch him do
it and from from that point really is
where my my interest peaked and I
figured you know this is way more fun
than school and homework. I want to be
doing this.
>> Wow. Oh. So, what year was that when
your father was introducing you to uh to
crypto?
>> Oh, man. I believe it was maybe 2014 or
2015.
>> Wow. So, he was a he was really an early
mover uh in crypto. That was back when
um when it was a very obscure.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. He was one of the
early adopters. I remember him going on
about it for forever and I didn't I
didn't really take him seriously. I'm
like, "Oh, it's just a online coin. No
one's going to want this."
>> Right. And so, did you uh did you have
any attraction to putting any of your
money into any of these coins or or or
did you just follow him? Just see what
he did?
>> Yeah. So, I I just followed him and
then, you know, I saved up birthday
money as a young child. And then
eventually, I think I saved up like a
$100 just from, you know, gifts from
aunts and uncles and I just put it in
his account with him and he let me uh
buy some of the the altcoins. There's
obviously Bitcoin and then there was
Ethereum, Litecoin was a popular one
back then and uh that was really my
first experience into the world of
investing.
>> Wow. And so were you tempted to um to
trade it frequently like uh day trading
it or were you more of a kind of a buy
and hold because you thought there was
some uh future potential?
>> Uh so in reality I didn't know much of
what I was doing, you know, just just
young me. I was looking at the charts. I
thought I knew what I was doing
definitely. Um but it it would really
just depend on on how busy I was with
school, what I had going on. I remember
just coming home every single day and if
I if I had time I would go go into the
account would buy I would sell I would
do all of these random actions that
probably were more negative than
positive. Uh but in my mind I was
increasing the gain.
>> Oh wow. So your early experiences were
uh were positive in trading.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So um it was very hard to
lose money in that stage with crypto.
Everything was just going straight up
all the time. Realistically, if I just
held and didn't make any transactions at
all, it would have been a lot better.
But, uh, in my mind, I just saw the
numbers go up, so I'm like, "Oh, hey, I
must be a genius."
>> Yeah. So, uh, tell us about your first
loss or draw down in crypto and how did
it feel?
>> Uh, so the first draw down that would
have been in probably the crash of I
believe it was 2016,
uh, near the end of that four-year
cycle. And that was the first time I
really understood that, oh uh these
things go up, they can also come down
just as fast. And uh to me it wasn't it
wasn't a huge hit just because we were
able to get in so early. But it was very
very jolting just to see the value of
the account drop, you know, 50 50% in
just a matter of weeks.
>> Yeah. Wow. And so are you kind of
shadowing uh your father in all his
trades? Were you pretty much uh doing
close to identical trades or were you
more off on your own?
>> I was mostly off on my own. I did shadow
him for the first I'd say month. Uh but
realistically he was smarter than me. He
just bought the quality ones and held on
to them forever. I had a lot of fun just
going experimenting, buying, selling,
doing all of those useless actions. Um
but you know, it's it's how I learned a
lot. So glad it happened. Was there any
particular type of strategy or you were
just following the technicals on the
chart or did you have a a method uh to
what you were doing at all or just just
experimenting?
>> Just experimenting at that stage. So I
was still around 14 15 years old. If I
saw something going up super fast uh
that would be my cue to buy in.
>> Wow. Great. So um how long did you um
stay with the crypto and and did you
ever consider um given your initial
positive experiences venturing out into
stocks or commodities or any other
asset?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Of course. So from then um
we had I stayed with crypto for a little
bit and then I got into stocks next and
then from stocks you know I had a
portfolio and again my my dad is the one
that introduced me to stocks. Um, at
first I was solely focused on crypto. I
didn't really I knew stocks were a
thing. I didn't just pay much attention
to it. Uh, and he had an account about
$3,000 in a Robin Hood account at this
time. This was maybe two years later.
Uh, and he just said, "Hey, you know, if
you want to invest this, do your
research, be careful with it, but I
would love for you to take it over."
And, uh, I I did exactly that. So,
that's kind of my transition from crypto
to stocks.
And uh you transitioned from crypto to
stocks because you were just kind of
curious about trying a new market or did
you feel disappointed at all uh with
crypto by the end?
>> A little bit of both. So I definitely
did want to try that new market but
absolutely that happened with crypto
after that draw down. I kind of took a
break for couple of months you know for
first big loss for every trader I feel
like it's a little bit disheartening.
Um, so I just didn't trade, you know, I
was focused on school, focused on work,
other things and yeah, got back into
stocks. Um, a little bit after that, the
year was probably 2019 at that point,
right before COVID. Uh, and that was,
you know, so a good time has has elapsed
between the crypto and stock transition.
>> So, uh, tell us a little bit about your
early stock experiences, uh, your
methodology, if you had any, what did
you look at, what did you invest or
trade? Yeah. So, when I first got into
stocks, I remember uh I was about 17
years old. I was working at Chipotle at
that time, making $8 an hour. And I had
a portfolio that my father had given me
of $3,000. And I really just invested
in, you know, classical investing
advice, a diversified portfolio. You
know, I had gold, blue chip stocks,
things of that nature. And I loved it
because I would make $8 an hour at my
job, but then I would pull up my
portfolio during my break and I would
see, oh, well, I'm up $100 over here.
This is way better.
>> Um, yeah. So, were you um did you look
at then more of a kind of a buy and hold
approach or did you dive deep into
different ways of trading?
>> Yeah. So at that period uh I I really
went very focused into the buy and hold
approach. I subscribed to so many
fundamental analysis newsletters. I was
reading Warren Buffett books. Everything
I could do just to figure out how to,
you know, even read a balance sheet and
do all these things that really mattered
in the long run. Uh but eventually I I
did get tired of going on social media
and seeing people have 100% gains in a
day and I'm like, well, how is that
possible? And then eventually I
inevitably switched to the dark side and
started trading options.
>> Oh wow. You you jumped from a more of a
longterm buy and hold to trading
options. Is that uh because of what you
saw in those videos, those seductive
videos?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So, you know,
there's me as 17 years old and I'm
seeing on Instagram just all of these
people with with Lamborghinis and yachts
and boats and all all of these uh the
trading gurus, the classic ones you'll
see online who, you know, in hindsight a
lot of them are probably not not knowing
what they're talking about. But to me,
that was like, wow, I want I want
exactly that. And I ended up buying a
course from this one individual who did
solely options trading. Uh and that
that's really what got me into it.
>> Mhm. And what uh so is this uh still
2019 just before COVID?
>> Yeah. So this is 2019 right before the
crash. So uh you know around that time
whatever the date would be.
>> Uh so tell us about uh some of these
early option trades. What kind of
strategies uh did you get into?
>> Yeah. So uh I mean learning options
itself is obviously a a very a very hard
thing to do. So, um I I remember staying
up like all night for a week straight
just learning at uh learning the Greeks,
learning the option structures, just
everything. The first time I pulled up
even an options chain, I had no idea
what I was looking at, right? So, um
just I spent the first week learning and
then eventually um my strategy was very
similar to crypto. I guess you could now
classify it as breakout trading or
momentum trading, whatever you want to
call it, where I would just go on these
usually penny stocks that were up 50% in
the day. And my my thesis behind the
trades were, well, it's up 50% right
now. Uh what keeps it from going up
another 50%. Uh and again, in hindsight,
maybe not the best thing to do, but uh
that was definitely my early learning
curve.
>> Well, you mentioned penny stocks. Are
there really many penny stocks that also
have options on them or was that a were
they separate endeavors that you got
into?
>> No. So, the penny stocks that I trade, I
I did options on them. Um, a lot of them
don't have options on them and you know,
back then I didn't even know that. It's
probably not the brightest idea just
because of the implied volatility that
you're paying against. You know, there's
obviously the huge spread on those. So,
you're automatically at a loss from the
start. I remember entering trades and
being down like 40% right right on the
entry and I'm like you know why why does
why does this happen so a lot of flaws
with that strategy?
>> So I mean you were down uh so much right
out of the gate. Did you just place
market orders and get bad fills or was
the bid ass spread just obscenely wide?
A
>> little bit of both. Yeah. So I I did
market orders because I didn't really
even know how to properly structure a
limit order. I I've tried in the past
and I I wouldn't get filled and it just
was a turnoff for me. So I only sto only
only took to market orders exclusively.
So obviously the bid ass spread and then
just not timing the market very well,
buying the highs and then there's a
pullback. Just a combination of
everything. Everything that could
possibly go wrong was going wrong at
that time.
>> Upon reflecting back at that time, did
you feel that you had um like some
impatience? uh the urge to rush to get
into the trade and thus that therefore
it's like that's why you placed the
market order.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That that was definitely a
big part of it. I just saw the stock was
going up and you know instead of waiting
for a pullback or confirmed breakout,
whatever technical signal I might base
my trade off of now, I just I didn't
want to miss it. I was very greedy and
still at this stage really didn't have a
real strategy. So, uh really just
throwing blind darts at this point. And
so the option course that you uh signed
up for uh the instructor was teaching
people how to uh play options on penny
stocks specifically.
>> So he actually wouldn't teach a specific
strategy. It was more just how to buy
options, what the Greeks mean, all all
of these sorts of things. Uh it was a
whole like one of those trading
communities and they did do trade call
outs and things of that nature. And
later down the line, I did start
adopting a strategy very similar to to
theirs, just learning from their
callouts. Uh, so I did end up flipping
to more of a swing trading strategy, a
contrarian based strategy where I would
use indicators like bullinger bands,
RSI, uh, divergences specifically, and I
would look for bullish divergences to
line up with the Ballinger bands, look
for some type of reversal play on the
daily chart. Uh and that was really when
I first developed my my own strategy
with its own set of rules. Uh and that's
what took my trading from complete
guesswork to actually first beginning to
build the system.
>> So this was a a a process that you kind
of developed yourself.
>> Right. Exactly. I got the base knowledge
of options from the course and then just
by putting together so many YouTube
tutorials, the the callouts in that
trading community and then other stuff I
would see online. Uh, I just got
together a list of my favorite
indicators that I've seen from
everywhere and mushed it all into one
very roughly done strategy. Do you
remember uh any early trades that you
did buying calls on these high-flying uh
penny stocks? Uh, can you recall any
ticker symbols or stories that uh you
might be able to share and uh your
experiences?
>> The penny stocks aren't aren't too
memorable. uh didn't have much success
with them, but also no huge failures, so
nothing sticks out to me. Um, one of the
first real divergence plays that I took
that I remember just because it was such
a fantastic win, uh, was on Paramount,
which back then was, I believe, Viacom.
The ticker was, uh, VIAC, and it had a
huge runoff. Uh, and it was just super
extended. you could tell that, you know,
it was um it was it was almost the exact
opposite of my previous strategy where I
would have went long at that point just
because of how much it had went up. Uh
it was every day it was another green
day and eventually uh it fit my strategy
rules. We had a divergence. We had it
tapping on the upper Ballinger band and
I figured, you know, this is very
extended and that is where I I bought
puts and it was just dumb luck that that
very next day uh they had an
announcement that they were filing for
bankruptcy or some other type of very
negative news. I don't know what it was.
Uh but the stock just absolutely
collapsed. I think they had over a 50%
draw down in just three days and those
puts ended up going something crazy like
6,000%.
Uh and that was one of my first trades
using that strategy. So it was very very
very memorable.
>> Wow. So 6,000% return. I mean you must
have been uh buying what? Out of the
money puts uh very shortdated. Is that
>> Yeah. So yeah. Yeah. Definitely weekly
puts very short expiration and out of
the money. Correct.
Um, so that's uh for you to go out on a
whim and because that is obviously a
risky options play. How to what degree
were your successes up to that point
that gave you the confidence to um to go
out of the money and be shortdated?
Because that goes against what a lot of
option gurus say is, oh no, you want to
buy options that are, you know, very
high delta longterm options because you
can lose your shirt on them. So,
>> right. Yeah. So, my strategy, and again,
it was still very new at this point for
me switching to it. So, it was more of
what I like to call the lottery ticket
strategy where I would take 10 types of
those plays. Uh, nine of them probably
wouldn't do so good. I would either let
them go to zero or get stopped out. Uh
but those one and 10 would just
absolutely take off and pay for you know
the previous nine losses. I would count
myself as barely profitable at that
stage. Nothing significant at all. Not
beating the market. Uh but you know
still still part of that very large
learning curve. It did take me longer
than most to to finally become
profitable.
>> You mentioned earlier about your foray
into uh penny stocks. It sounded like
you you didn't gain much, you didn't
lose much, uh but yet you're
um dabbling in a very volatile asset
with options uh that many people can get
their account wiped out. Did you have
any do you feel was it just dumb luck or
did you have a method like a
riskmanagement protocol?
>> Uh so for a solid year it was just dumb
luck including that trade. You know,
obviously I couldn't have predicted that
news was going to come out. Uh and then
after that, the next noticeable one, I
believe, I did catch the
>> the GameStop move coming downwards. So,
m missed it on the way up, but caught it
on the way down. And uh I took my
portfolio from 3,000 all the way up to
80,000 in about six months. And this is
still me at a 17year-old child working
at Chipotle. So, uh I I quit my job at
that point. I was on top of the world. I
remember every day I would be looking at
cars, what car I'm going to buy, looking
at $10,000 watches online, and then uh
finally after one very terrible trade of
me almost fulling my account on uh XPEV
uh an EV stock from China, I blew my
entire account and went back under
3,000. I believe I got stopped out
around $500 is where I sold. So that was
that was how I blew my account after all
that.
>> Wow. Well, what a story. Uh so sounds
like your your account was kind of
flatline or you didn't make huge gains
or take take huge losses prior to the
COVID crash and the and the the meme
stock craze.
>> Correct. Right.
>> Interesting. So, uh, so your performance
was kind of what you say more or less
flatlined, but you still had the
confidence to go in on these risky bets
and you didn't get burned. So, you
didn't get you didn't have any early
account blowups or or trauma uh in the
early years. Is that accurate?
>> Yeah, that's that's absolutely accurate.
And I I do believe that's why I ended up
blowing my entire portfolio because uh
the strategy overall um I I did have a
high win rate. If I just knew how to
manage risk, I probably would have been
fine. Um but, you know, I did get cocky
and and once I doubled my account and
got it to roughly, you know, nine
$10,000. I just figured like, oh, I have
it all figured out. I'm just going to
fullport my account on every trade. And
that that was how I even got to $80,000
in such a short amount of time. Uh, and
obviously when you're fullporting your
account, you're always one trade away
from demise. And I took it one trade too
far.
>> So, how did the the crash of uh 2020,
the COVID crash, how did you fare during
that? And what kind of positions were
you in?
>> I didn't really trade throughout that
entire thing because I was uh really
just a little bit too nervous to be
doing the option plays at that time. So,
and it it was a fairly quick crash.
Obviously, it happened very fast. Uh but
really once it bottomed out and then you
know a week or so went by and it started
rebounding that's when I gained the
confidence to really start taking trades
again. So you know in hindsight if I was
trading in the middle of all that I
probably would have blown my account
much faster learned the lesson earlier
and not have to had dealt with all of
that pain later but you know just
completely missed out on that and
learned it later down the line. So, I
imagine given how long that you've been
following the options market uh during
the crash of uh 2020, you couldn't help
but notice the implied volatilities uh
uh the prices of the options going
skyhigh. Did you ever want to change
your strategy from just going straight
long calls or uh were you fine just
sticking with that even when the the
implied volatility was so high and the
the options were so expensive? Right.
So, yeah, actually, um I do remember
staring at uh I traded on Robin Hood
back then and every time you open the
the ticker on Robin Hood. It'll show you
the options and it'll show you the the
gains and losses you would have had if
you were in it. And I remember every
single day opening Robin Hood and puts
are up like 500% almost every single
day. So, uh, from that point forward,
uh, I actually preferred trading puts
just because, um, you know, now I know
the the science behind how they
appreciate faster due to volatility
compared to calls. Uh, but back then I
wasn't aware about all the other
idiosyncrasies like they they decay
faster to theta compared to calls as
well because there's the crash risk. Uh,
but all of these things I I only saw
reflected in the gains and losses. I
didn't know the intricacies. uh but I
did actually prefer to trade puts and
that's actually what followed uh why I
did prefer on stocks like Viacom and
then GameStop to trade them to the
downside instead of try to catch the
move up.
>> So you you said that you were hesitant
about uh being in the market when the
market was was crashing and that you
waited later uh right for the market to
stabilize. Well, then the market started
going back up and and since you liked
being in puts kind of what were your um
trades as a market began to stabilize
and go back up, how were you able to
work with the puts in that situation?
>> Uh so essentially just finding those um
really just sticking to my strategy at
that point. That's when I had a good
grasp to it. So really just waiting for
those indications to line up. I wanted a
huge huge rally ideally on very high
volatility. I wanted it to be hitting my
upper Ballinger bands. I wanted a
bearish RSI divergence. All of these
indicators that I just put together into
one roughly built trading system. Uh and
as soon as it would signal, I didn't
really take into account the the overall
direction of the market. I didn't look
at relative strength compared to the
indexes. I just figured, you know, my my
signals fired. I probably should be in
this. and it worked fairly well. Uh but
obviously, you know, as I went on
through the years, I realized that
there's there could be a lot of
optimization in all this.
>> So, you're taking a very short-term bets
on particular stocks, individual stocks
that are way overextended according to
your technicals and for a very shortterm
uh drop or describe uh the time frames
and everything.
>> Right. Yeah. So, I would be looking at
it on the daily chart. That's where I
would want my divergence to be. That's
where I would want the upper Ballinger
band to hit. And then ideally, I would
only hold for about two to three days
and just sell sell my puts at the
nearest support level. Whether or not it
broke after that, you know, I was
typically out by then, but the the winds
were pretty sizable anywhere from 100 to
200% just because of how risky I was
going with the expirations.
>> So, your count of 3,000. um describe the
time frame that you rode the $3,000
account up to the peak of 80,000. Uh how
many months or years was that?
>> So was it was about five to six months.
It happened very fast again just because
I had no concept of risk management. Um
and yeah, I would just same thing look
at these daily charts, wait for all of
those signals to fire, fullport my
account or at least put a very big chunk
of it. uh sometimes I would be in
multiple trades at once say three or
four and uh those three or four
constitute the entire 100% of the
account uh but always very very large
bets in terms of percentage of my
portfolio. So over a six-month period,
you ran your account up 3,000 to 80,000
u and you by placing big bets, short
very short-term bets, buying puts on
these high-f flyers that are
overextended.
Uh did you have any um strategy to get
out uh of a losing position or were you
fortunate enough to happen to pick the
right ones and your big winners would uh
outweigh your hopefully small losers?
Chat with Traders is brought to you by
Tasty Trade. Tired of trading on rookie
apps? Then get the platform for serious
trading. Tasty Trade. Tasty Trade gives
you the tools to trade your way. Chart
your heart out with over 300 indicators.
Know your odds with probability of
profit and move fast with Quick Roll.
Trade what you want and trade it your
way. Stocks, options, futures, and more.
All in one account on one platform. No
wonder why serious traders choose Tasty
Trade. Visit tastyrade.com and see for
yourself. Tasty Trade Inc. is a
registered broker dealer and member of
ThinRa NFA and SIPC,
>> right? Yeah. So, uh I would I would call
it unfortunate that I didn't have a
system and you know it just had a high
win rate. Uh because if I did have a
system or I did learn the hard way on on
how these losses should have worked
again, I probably wouldn't have loan the
full account down the line. Uh but
realistically I would just let 90% of
them go to zero. If they were really
really taking off I would kind of just
add to the position over and over. Uh
and essentially you're almost bound to
get a bit of a draw down eventually. Um
especially when you're looking at such a
short time frame maybe the stock is
going to continue to go up but you buy
puts at open and it just has a very
quick flush. Uh but since you've been
dollar cost averaging in that that's all
you need. you can get out for about
break even and then the stock continues
higher. So, uh that's what I would
always hope to happen. That was kind of
my methodology, but again, if we didn't
get that, then it would essentially
really just go to zero. So, it was
terrible risk management.
>> Oh, I see. Um so, describe the the meme
stock craze. What did you do with that?
Uh were you ever tempted to go long? I
mean, quick way to make some money,
right, with some calls? You know, at
that point, I was so focused on just a
contrarian trading mindset where I
wasn't even considering longs at at any
point on GameStop. I did try to short it
once and I I lost a huge amount of my
account. It was like a 20% draw down in
one trade. Uh but then luckily, you
know, I was I was patient and I knew
that, you know, this this has to end
eventually. Uh so got got in one more
time and that that was the big one that
hit. Uh got a pretty sizable win on
that. It was about, I believe, 200% on a
huge red day. Uh, but regardless, the
the implied volatility was just so high
that I I bought the put so overpriced
and it it should have been a lot more.
And back then, I was still kind of
confused on why it's such a big move,
only yielded 200% when it really should
have done uh something way higher, maybe
like a,000%. Uh, but I ended up did
getting that win, locking it in. Uh, so
that kind of offset the pro offset the
loss, excuse me, from from the previous
trade.
>> And still you're you're sticking with uh
just straight puts almost regardless of
how high the IV uh was because this was
working for you and you decided to stick
with it,
>> right? Yeah. Exactly.
So upon reflection, when you reflected
back on those trades, did was there ever
a time then that you said, "Hey, maybe I
should venture out and try different
types of option strategies depending on
the IV or what's going on with the
stock."
>> After that trade actually is when I
focused on how the IV worked and really
took the time to understand it. And
that's when I got into really going
going long on stocks. This was a whole
another strategy. I kind of I don't want
to say abandoned the old one. I still
traded it here and there when the
opportunity showed themselves. But uh my
next strategy was a little bit
different. I wanted compression in
stocks that were trending upwards and
then I would buy during that compression
period when there's consolidation and
essentially there I'm buying in low
volatility periods and I would wait for
a breakout uh and I would sell on that
breakout capitalize off of the delta
move of course and spot price and then I
would also get the the added benefits
from the increase in the volatility
>> and uh those were were they short-term
trades as well? How what kind of time
frame? So those would be anywhere from 0
to 5 days. I would like to trade the the
hourly and the daily chart on those.
>> Uh okay. So with your account at 80,000
after 6 months. Uh describe how it all
blew up.
>> It was at 80,000 and uh that was the
peak as I mentioned. I thought I was on
top of the world making my shopping
list. Uh and then as I mentioned the
ticker was XPEV that that company that
um you know it just didn't go so well. I
saw that it had a dip. And these were
actually calls. So these these I was
going long on. And it was a little bit
of a, you know, I'm unstoppable. I can
buy whatever I want and my trade will
work. So I I got into calls on a dip.
And you know, everyone has the same
story. You buy the dip and it keeps on
dipping. So I averaged down two, three,
four, five times until my entire
portfolio was in on it. and I just
couldn't bring myself to sell because
with my previous strategy, I was so used
to, you know, all it takes is one spike
and and I can get out at break even. Uh
but in this case, we didn't really get
the spike. It was just absolutely
selling off with no hesitation and I
finally cut it at $500 left in my
account from the 80,000 and it all went
away in one single trade.
>> Oh my god. Wow. So, how long was it uh
did did it take to go from 80,000 back
down to almost nothing.
>> Pretty quickly, actually. Only about a
week and a half.
>> What was your mental state at the time?
I mean, did did you feel like quitting
trading altogether or?
>> Uh, no. So, I was definitely a little
bit down in the dumps to put it lightly.
But, um, my my mindset was, you know,
this this wasn't my money. This was my
my father's money. I lost him $3,000.
Uh, so I'm going to do whatever I need
to do. I'm going to I make it back. You
know, it might take a little bit. Might
be hard, but I was very determined on
making it back.
>> So, what year was this that you
>> This was about just just into the start
of 2021 now.
>> Oh, okay. So, wow. So, this is very
short time period. Um, this all occurred
during the the runup. So, so describe
what um what did you do in 2021? Yeah.
So 2021 that that strategy I just
mentioned about the consolidation
periods that's when I started learning
that uh and again that experience is
kind of why I fell uh fell out of love
with that uh divergent strategy just
because it it didn't work. It had a
really left a really bad taste in my
mouth. So switched to the consolidation
periods. Uh liked really just trailing
the the EMAs the 10 and the 21. I would
want that. I would want the MACD
crossing. I would want volume to be
super low during the consolidation and
then see a spike on the breakout. Uh and
that was just very a very very easy
strategy to do. You have the trend in
your favor. Uh it's very easy to spot.
There's lots of opportunities all the
time. There's always something that's
trending. Uh and that you know I've seen
a lot of success with that really early
on and that's when I fell in love with
it. I still trade that strategy to this
day even. Um but yeah, that I was able
to get the 500 back up to 3,000 in about
6 months.
>> And uh how do you find these um tightly
consolidating stocks? Is there a
particular screening tool that you use
or
>> Yeah, so I actually custom built a
screener in the Thinker Swim platform
and essentially it would search for
squeezes which are when it uses the
Ballinger bands and Kelner channels. Uh,
and I would add a few more little
details as well, but those two would
essentially put it on the watch list. I
had a few filters with volume and I I
didn't want any small cap stocks, no
penny stocks. I liked very liquid stocks
with short or not not very wide spreads
because I didn't want to get terrible
entries. Uh, and those were essentially
just put up on my watch list every day
and I would take the best one um every
single day. I typically did about one
trade a day. If I was already in a trade
from the previous day, I wouldn't really
look to enter anything, but if there was
something that was just perfect, uh I
could possibly be in, you know, two or
three trades at once.
>> And again, you're holding them for very
short time frames and and if so, were
you ever tempted to uh hold on for the
longer term?
>> Those I would hold from about zero to
five days. Uh some of them I I did see
them running even past those five days.
I did try holding some of them. Uh I
didn't really like it too much because
inevitably, you know, some of them they
would roll over and you end up giving
back a large portion of your profit,
sometimes even all your profit if you
don't trail it properly using the EMAs.
Uh so I really just stuck to selling
into strength at any key resistance
level and um you know that obviously
gives the best return when you're taking
volatility into account as well. So, I
tended to stick with that on the daily
and hourly chart specifically.
>> Okay. So, so you you have this new
strategy now and you're uh building your
account back up, get it back up to 3,000
and then once you got there, you just
continued with um with that. I mean, h
how did the rest of 2021 uh go for you?
>> Right. Yeah. So, I really just uh kept
spamming that strategy day after day. I
was able to build the account back up.
uh and really just grow it from there.
uh that's really when I first started
even becoming profitable is when I had a
first strategy that you know I
understood the risks and everything and
that's also when the the most important
factor I know everyone talks about it
and everyone is tired of hearing it but
uh risk management really is the most
important part of trading and and that's
when I had a good grasp on how it worked
uh and you know the exponential effects
of these drawdowns and um yeah so from
2021 all the way up until I'd say 2024
for early 2024, I I specifically only
traded that strategy and uh that that's
when I was really profitable right
there. So, was your risk management just
being patient and avoiding the tempting
uh plays, but uh that did not fit your
profile and just waiting it out until
the great setups appeared.
>> Uh so, not not specifically, no. Um, so
I would take most of the setups that
that came across. I I did obviously
prefer the higher quality setups as
would any trader, but the way that I did
it was not to avoid the maybe mediocre
ones completely, but just allocate a
different position size. So, I would
always rate the setups on a scale from 1
to 10 on how much I like them. So, if
I'm looking at a setup that's maybe a
six out of 10, maybe I would risk 1% on
it. Uh, and at this point, I was still
fairly aggressive. So, if I saw
something like a 10 out of 10 setup, the
most I would risk is 5% of my portfolio
on it. Uh, and you know, obviously those
quality setups, they have a much higher
win rate. Uh, and just using that method
of really really being careful about the
position sizing, being very, very picky
on which stocks to enter and what
position size based off all the
confluences. Uh, that's really what did
it for me.
>> So, how did uh 2021 end for you?
So 2021 nothing too crazy. I did about
30% that year. Uh don't remember if that
beat the market but um that you know the
markets has been very bullish over the
past five years. Uh but you know I was I
was very happy with it. It was my first
entire year that I was profitable. So I
always remember that as kind of the the
turning point for me. And uh so you
stuck with just simply uh going long um
call options uh for a very short term.
And uh once you fully grasp the whole IV
situation, were you ever tempted to uh
short out of the money calls with
sky-high IVs on some of these uh bubble
stocks?
>> Surprisingly, no. Uh I just don't like
the idea. I didn't like it at all. I
still don't like it. I have never
shorted a call. Um just the idea of the
risk-to-reward. I've also never shorted
a naked put. Uh I will do credit spreads
and things of those nature, but um I
like the risk to be capped at a certain
extent. I like knowing the worst
possible scenario. Uh I just hate the
idea of having the unlimited downside on
a position.
>> So great. So you you stuck with this uh
strategy. Um, and how did it go in um,
2022 and what um, you you still stuck
with that uh, breakout strategy?
>> Yeah, so I was I was sticking with that.
In 2022, I did 49%. In 2023, I did much
better. I did I believe it was 103%. So
that was, you know, one of one of my
better years. Uh, and then, you know,
after that, it was typically anywhere
from the range of 50 to 100%.
um ve very very contingent on the amount
of setups I got and obviously uh my my
trade size that I'm putting on these
setups and that's all based off
discretionary actions like how how good
I think the setup is just based off you
know the price action things of that
nature. Uh later down the line I was
able to quantify it but back then it was
more uh just just intuition at that
point. And so do you attribute the
higher returns in uh 2023 uh versus the
earlier years uh due to any kind of
refinement or do you just getting better
at at picking out um the high quality
trades, the nuances behind it or do you
feel it was just kind of the market kind
of luck that you had those higher
returns?
>> I would love to say that I sat here and
got much better at trading. That would
be fantastic. um would certainly make me
look good. But in all reality, uh that
that year, just looking back at my
trades, I I keep a journal of all my
trades, um you know, I just had an
exceptionally high win rate. I didn't
really do anything special or change
anything. Uh the market was just in
favor of the strategy at that time. And
I'm sure every trader knows, uh
strategies will go through great periods
and they'll also go through periods
where they underperform. Uh and you just
have to take it for what it is. So with
with that year, I I was fortunate to be
a little bit lucky. I had the market on
my side.
>> Um that was 2023 when the market
recovered off the bare market lows and
started going back up, right? So that
the the wind at your back uh helped you
um with those that kind of call option
strategy,
>> right? Yeah, it definitely helped a ton,
you know, trading with the trend of the
overall market, matching with the
indices. I did take into account
strength at that time. That's actually
when I first started learning about it.
So, I was able to use that as an
advantage. I'm sure that, you know,
helped a considerable amount, but
definitely not uh definitely can't
attribute that to all of the extra
success.
>> So, you were successful enough with the
stock market. Did you ever feel tempted
to uh go back to crypto or any other
markets or you just stuck to your bread
and butter?
>> So, I just stuck to options from from
that point forward. I just loved
options. the the main point was how the
volatility works. Um I I just thought it
was amazing how you could really just be
in a very mediocre trade, but the
volatility increases and you're on the
right side, you pick the right strike
prices, you can just get outsized
returns compared to crypto futures,
really anything else in the world.
>> How did your trading go for uh what year
are we on to now? 2024, 2025. Yeah. So
2024 I had a fantastic year partly due
to luck. So towards the end of the year
around November I was up around 80%. So
still a still a great year. Um but then
after that I had a fantastic trade on
gold actually trading options on the
gold index and there was one single
trade on that that took me from 80% on
that year to 580%
by by the end of the year. So, uh, it
went extraordinarily well, but again,
you know, it was it was a large part
luck. Uh, but, uh, you know, o overall
very happy with it regardless.
>> So, gold tends to, uh, move rather, uh,
slowly over time, uh, generally
trending, um, market. What What did you
do specifically to get such a big win
out of out of gold? Yeah. So, I mean, it
was bought in sort of a consolidation
period and then we did have a little bit
of a dip back to the exponential moving
averages, which is what I like to see.
And then during that period, um, you
know, we had we had the volume kind of
confirming that the that the bounce was
ending. I had a long-term support line
drawn out. Um, and I I risked the entire
5%. It's what I classified as a A+
setup, a 10 out of 10. And it just
bounced super hard. And these were
weekly options. So, um you know, it just
absolutely took off.
>> During this journey, are you sharing uh
any of this with uh friends or family?
And uh and if so, uh what were their
reactions?
>> Uh so, not really. You know, I liked to
keep it a little bit private. Um I
didn't really want my my friends knowing
what I did. Uh I really started to share
it just recently in in 2025.
um just from trading for about six to
seven years at this point. Um starting
with crypto all the way up until 2025.
Uh I actually opened my my hedge fund.
And uh when I opened that hedge fund, I
actually decided, you know, I'm probably
going to need investors. I should
probably start advertising my returns,
telling my friends, my family, my
colleagues. Uh and that's when I started
publicizing all of it.
>> Excuse the last interruption here. This
is Tessa. We hope you're enjoying this
episode so far. If you love the podcast,
please give Chat with Traders the best
review you can on whatever platform
you're listening from. This will help us
to keep the episodes coming. Also, if
you haven't subscribed to our email
list, please hop on to
chatwithtraders.com
and click on subscribe so we can keep
you posted of information that may be of
importance. Thank you. Now, back to the
chat with our guest.
>> So, what uh what goes into actually
starting a a hedge fund? Is it a lot of
paperwork and um how did you do it?
>> A lot of paperwork, compliance, and too
much talking to attorneys, but um
obviously I'm sure people are aware it's
a very expensive thing to do. So that's
why I felt it was such a great time to
do it after such a great year. Um but in
reality, I knew I wanted to start a
hedge fund since I was very early into
trading, just getting that first taste
of of options really. Um, so it was a
goal for a while and then once I had
that great year, I decided, you know, I
have enough capital now, I have enough
confidence in my trading. Um, and I'm
sure if people see these numbers for the
past few years, they would love to
invest. So that's really what got me
started on it. And then, you know, we
worked on it. It took about six months
to launch. And we actually got our first
launch date of this year in May 8th to
be exact.
>> Oh wow. Well, congratulations on that
journey. So with the strategy that you
use, have you figured out is there kind
of an upper limit on how much money you
can uh easily deploy?
>> Yeah. So we we actually use a a lot of
strategies at at the at the hedge fund.
We're classified as a multi strategy
hedge fund. Our aum that we would cap
out at is at 150 million. So we foresee
us being able to operate perfectly
smoothly for at least another three to
five years. And then once we get to that
point, our strategies would cap out just
because of the liquidity issues. And uh
from there, you know, there are a bunch
of solutions, but we're most likely
going to have to start really just
distributing profits back to investors
at that point or closing the fund down.
Uh but, you know, we probably wouldn't
choose that unless we're ready to
retire.
>> Oh, yeah. Uh so, you mentioned other
strategies. uh what other what other
strategies did you get into and um kind
of why and how much experience do you
have with them?
>> All all the strategies I'll just list
them out very quickly. We do have a
version of the original one, the swing
trading strategy where you want to look
for a divergence and and all of these
signals with the Ballinger bands. Uh, an
example of that would be uh about two
weeks ago, we had a fantastic swing
trade on Meta where it it gapped down
and it just slowly trended down. I'm
sure you and tons of other people have
seen that. Everyone watches Meta. Uh,
and it it ended up shooting up and
exactly like like like we like uh it
happens very quick with with big
candles. The volatility goes up. Uh, so
that that's the one strategy we use. Uh,
swing trading strategy. We only really
get about one trade a month on that one,
but you know, we keep it. We love it.
It's very easy to monitor, so no point
in not using that one. Uh the second one
is the next strategy I learned after
that, the breakout one that we just
talked about. And then we use two more.
And those two are shorter term zero DTE
strategies. Uh the first one what we do
is our spin on the classic break and
retest where we'll mark out the
pre-market high and pre-market low. And
this is traded on SPY QQQ and the blue
chip stocks. Uh and we like to do uh
single leg calls or debit spreads on
these zero DTE every single time. We
want to break and retest. We have all of
these indicators with high volume ATR
measures. Uh we use the RSI. We use
something called the DSS Resert
indicator which is one of my favorite
ones. Uh but whole whole bunch of things
go into that and we really only hold
those trades for about 5 to 15 minutes.
And that one is one of our highest
performing our second highest performing
one. Uh our first and our our flagship
strategy of the entire fund. Uh what we
do actually is zero DTE butterflies on
the S&P. Uh and we won't trade them on
SPY. Well, we'll look at the chart on
SPY because you can obviously look at
the extended hours. Uh you don't get
that on SPX. Uh additionally, SPX is
cash settled, so you won't be left
hanging with anything. Uh and what we do
is we look at these gamma heat maps. We
take into account charm. Uh all of these
market maker tools. We use something
specific called options depth with shows
it. And we've also created our our own
tools. And essentially what we do is
five to 10 width butterflies that will
pin and it only has a 52% win rate but
the average win on it is 950%.
Uh and as you know these butterflies so
every single trade will close anywhere
within 500 to 2,000% because they're so
narrow and you just get uh great
probabilities on them despite the 50 52%
win rate. And that is really the the
flagship one that we use.
>> And these are on short-term um zero DTE
spy options.
>> SPX only for
>> Yep. Correct. Correct.
>> Uhhuh. Um um that seems well that's
quite quite a high return for um for a
an an index that is so widely watched.
Uh
is there what do you attribute these
super high returns that you can get with
that? Um wouldn't everyone be doing this
because it's so widely um viewed,
>> right? You know, um I actually had no
idea about how this worked, but uh when
I was starting my my hedge fund, I was
obviously talking to a lot of lawyers
and a lot of other members of people now
that I'm very close friends with who had
hedge funds. And I met this one person
in in in particular and uh I remember
his his hedge fund was doing 500% every
single year for the past I think it was
like nine years and it just it blew my
mind that 580% was my best year by far
by absolute luck. Uh and this guy was
doing 500% consistently and I didn't
believe it at first. He showed me the
audited reports of his fund and
everything. And uh he he really taught
me so much about how to use things that
most most traders actually haven't heard
about. Uh you'd be surprised like these
gamma levels, charm, there's obviously
uh options Greeks. Um but there's
actually second degree derivatives,
there's third degree derivatives, and
there's fourth degree a single fourth
degree derivative of these as well. and
all of these that traders don't know
about. That is where we get essentially
our entire edge. Uh and we're able to
kind of exploit that advantage to get
very outsized returns.
>> Hey, quick note for context. After we
wrapped this interview, we followed up
with Jamal to clarify a few of the
performance figures that you just heard
and how some of the strategy details
were derived. on the example he
referenced of another fund doing roughly
500% annually. He told us he's not able
to share the name of that fund and
described it at a high level as a
breakoutbased approach using Fibonacci
retracements from key levels. Now, on
his own flagship strategy, he clarified
that it's been live traded for about
three years and that it is zero DTE
butterflies exclusively on the S&P
typically built with five or 10 point
wide structures. The underlying thesis,
as he described it, is centered around
where price may pin using what he
referred to as second level derivatives.
He also clarified the distribution of
outcomes. He stated that approximately
52% of trades fall into the large winner
range he described while the remaining
trades typically result in losses of
about 50 to 100% of the premium at risk.
And finally on risk adjusted metrics. He
said that due to his funds structure,
certain figures aren't shared publicly
and that any information he's able to
disclose is available on his website and
has been audited by a third party.
>> Um, wow, that's impressive. Uh, so, um,
how many how much assets under
management are you currently at?
>> So, we're currently right under 50.
>> Wow, fantastic. Uh so to wrap things up,
what do you struggle with most as a
trader and and now and in the past?
>> In the past it was, you know, as the war
stories may have indicated, it was most
definitely risk management. Um now it
it's really um a different set of
struggles where um I almost flip through
strategies too much. I want to develop
even more strategies and you know ever
since we got the most recent two our
fund has been doing great. Um and in my
head it's like okay well you know they
can always be better. Uh so I'm always
tweaking things and trying to change it
up and and usually the trades uh or the
the changes don't actually end up being
uh an optimization but it actually takes
the stats down. So, my biggest struggle
is kind of just uh you could kind of
classify it as discipline where I I
already know that a strategy works, but
um I just need to trust in the strategy,
stop trying to mess around with it, find
a hundred other things, uh to do and
just sit there, be patient, and wait for
the setups to happen.
>> What advice would you give to uh traders
who keep blowing up their accounts but
uh uh refuse to quit?
So, uh, as someone that struggled with
the the same thing, it would definitely
be practice risk management, um, when I
first heard that you're only supposed to
risk 2% of your account per trade, I was
like devastated. I would didn't know how
anyone was supposed to make money like
that. But, uh, really just make a set of
rules that will help you stick to it
and, you know, just stick to it from
that point. It's all about discipline.
>> Well, great. Uh Jamal, I'd like to thank
you for uh coming on chat with traders.
>> Absolutely. It's been an absolute
pleasure and I thank you for having me.
>> And how can our listeners get in touch
with you? Uh so you know we don't
actually have a public website or what
we do for our fund but specifically I
know a lot of gurus have the the trading
education channels which I don't have
but anyone is feel please feel free to
look me up on LinkedIn and shoot me a DM
and I'm more than happy to reply there.
>> Okay. And what what's your uh handle on
LinkedIn? It's just my my name Jamal
Gari and that's J A M A A L and then
Gari is G H A U R I.
>> Fantastic. Thanks for coming on the
show. Of course, my pleasure.
You've reached the end of this episode
of Chat with Traders, but rest assured
there are more episodes loaded with real
market insight and zero hype on the way
soon. So to stay updated with each great
new release, subscribe to the podcast in
iTunes. And we'd love it if you'd leave
a rating and review. We'll catch you
next time on Chat with Traders.
[Music]